<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan C. Mendoza</title>
    <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nathan C. Mendoza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 13:07:59 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathancmendoza.live/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Idea Bank</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/idea-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 13:07:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/idea-bank/</guid>
      <description>Source Code: https://github.com/orgs/idea-bank/repositories
Cumulative practice This is the final project that I worked on during my college career. It came at the end of the final year of my schooling and would be a cumulative way to demonstrate project management, software design and implementation, and soft skills. The project was not provided by a the school or an internal source. Instead, a project sponsor was recruited to provide a unique and challenging project for us to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmge</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/tmge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 12:49:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/tmge/</guid>
      <description>Source Code: https://github.com/orgs/inf122-tmge-winter-2023/repositories
Advanced software design project This project involved designing a software library that could be used to build tile matching games. The library needed to be extensible to cover both real-time and turn-based tile matching games. The final application needed to support multiplayer versions of tile-matching games, and provide a way to determine a winner and loser of each match.
This project was designed and implemented completely with in-house software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slice of Life</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/slice-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 12:21:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/slice-of-life/</guid>
      <description>Source Code: https://github.com/orgs/slice-of-life/repositories
Project management During a project management course that I took in my final year of college, I, along with a team, had to come up with a project that we would need to manage. The management course did not require to project to actually be completed, only artifact that demonstrate that the project could be successfully managed. However, a couple of team members decided the project idea sounded interesting enough and took a shot and implementing the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Calculator</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/scientific-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 11:55:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/projects/scientific-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Source Code: https://github.com/nathancmendoza/PyCalc
Using new skills The first real programming project that I decided to build outside of my course work was a calculator. This would eventually end up being a scientific calculator. By including functions like trigonometry and roots, this projects differs from the more straight forward desk calculator that one might find. Additionally, this project would also be my first experience with complex GUI creation.
I began working on this project during the summer between my first and second year of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering Internship</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/software-engineering-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 20:19:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/software-engineering-internship/</guid>
      <description>Active: 6/2022 - 9/2022
Some Real World Experience The summer between my third and fourth year of college, I applied for and was accepted for an internship at Box. During my short tenure at the company, I was part of the MySQL engineering team. This team is responsible for managing and automating various processes and services that makeup the database infrastructure that supports the company.
The internship was designed to have me work on a singular project throughout the 12 week program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Minds Instructor</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/coding-minds-instructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 19:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/coding-minds-instructor/</guid>
      <description>Active: 6/2022-6/2023
Fostering Programming in the Youth During my final year of schooling, I took a position to teach the basic a programming to younger students. These students were typically in elementary school age. A few students were middle or high school age. My role as a leading instructor had me teach and explain the basic of many programming topic. As the learning process is much different between young children and college students, the courses focused more on getting the children to write code that would work quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Tutor</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/student-tutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 18:29:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/student-tutor/</guid>
      <description>Active: 9/2020 - 6/2022
Helping others During college, I discovered an oppurtunity to help other students with coursework that I have already passed. This is beneficial for both me and the students that I helped. For me, it would be a good way to review the content that I have already covered. For the students, it provided them with a more relatable source to seek assistance with coursework (Talking to professors can sometimes can be daunting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Teller</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/student-teller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 17:31:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/experience/student-teller/</guid>
      <description>Active: 8/2018 - 5/2019
First professional computing During my final year of high school, the oppurtunity to work as a student teller at a campus branch became available. The branch was operated by Union Bank (now US bank) and allowed a select group of students to work as a bank teller. Since foot traffic at a bank situated inside a high school campus was limited to faculty and students, most of the work consisted of improving professional skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/education/college/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 17:21:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/education/college/</guid>
      <description>Active: 9/2019 - 6/2023
Next steps in a journey From September 2019 to June 2023 I attended the University of California, Irvine (UCI). Upon admission, I was accepted as a computer science major. However, I would eventually transition to become a Software Engineering major. The two majors are quite similar. They share many of the same courses and have a strong focus on the theoretical aspects of their respective fields.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High School</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/education/high-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 23:14:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/education/high-school/</guid>
      <description>Active: 8/2015-5/2019
The start of a journey From August 2015 for May 2019, I attended Loara HS in Anaheim, California. This time was filled with discovering new knowledge and and subjects. As with most people at this age, I had yet to consider what I wanted to do after high school. Fortunately, that question would be answered long before I graduated.
In the first two years, I began to believe that I would be doing something related to mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nathancmendoza.live/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:24:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancmendoza.live/about/</guid>
      <description>A Developer&amp;rsquo;s Journey Greetings, fellow developers and coding enthusiasts! Welcome to my digital realm, where lines of code intertwine with tales of growth and discovery. Today, we embark on a thrilling adventure into the world of software development, where our collective passion for innovation and mastery guides us toward new heights of expertise.
This site aims to share the collective information and experience that I have gathered throughout my early career as a software developer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
